<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taimur Hassan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Taimur Hassan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy: a Solution or a Problem in Sophocles’ Ajax</title>
      <link>/blog/democracy-a-solution-or-a-problem-in-sophocles-ajax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/democracy-a-solution-or-a-problem-in-sophocles-ajax/</guid>
      <description>A Short Narrative on Democracy in the Ajax
Democracy is a unique and interesting form of government which renders the populace as primarily responsible for their actions. It comes from the Greek roots’ “demos”, meaning people, and “kratos,” meaning power, an antithesis to aristocracy, “aristos,” meaning the best. In the case of Sophocles’ Ajax, a perspective of unjust democracy is addressed, but on most occasions, democracy proves to be largely successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Heroism Through the Lens of the Trojan War</title>
      <link>/blog/the-cost-of-heroism-through-the-lens-of-the-trojan-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-cost-of-heroism-through-the-lens-of-the-trojan-war/</guid>
      <description>What is The Cost of Heroism?
While modern interpretations render heroism distinctly in the category of the brave bordering to magnanimity, a strictly classical sense defines a hero as someone associated with the idea of glory (kleos). The epic poem Iliad by Homer describes heroism in a classical way, where heroism can lead to both brilliant feats and unflinching injustice. Iliad is a description of the Trojan War, and a prerequisite of winning a war is displaying fearless heroism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview of the Second-Wave of Feminism in Local Cities During the 1960s</title>
      <link>/blog/an-overview-of-the-second-wave-of-feminism-in-local-cities-during-the-1960s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/an-overview-of-the-second-wave-of-feminism-in-local-cities-during-the-1960s/</guid>
      <description>Feminism has been a major concern specifically for the American populace long before the advent of the civil rights movement. In early America, women tended to follow stereotypical roles and were seen as secondary to men. If any of them followed to increase their status by means of seeking profession or breaking the traditional gender stereotype, she would be shunned by the male-dominant society. A second-wave of feministic activism began in the 1960s and early 1970s causing a proliferation of feminist organizations across small cities, which inadvertently sought support from those in the larger metropolis in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look What I Found!</title>
      <link>/blog/look-what-i-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/look-what-i-found/</guid>
      <description>MY FIRST EVER GIF PROJECT. CLEARLY, THE MESSAGE IS DIFFICULT TO UNDERSTAND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutations in EFHC1 gene influencing brain development in patients with JME</title>
      <link>/blog/mutations-in-efhc1-gene-influencing-brain-development-in-patients-with-jme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mutations-in-efhc1-gene-influencing-brain-development-in-patients-with-jme/</guid>
      <description>Juvenile Myoclonic Epilepsy presents itself in adolescence, affecting the person’s well-being (Striano &amp;amp; Nobile, 2018). It presents itself in myoclonic jerks causing the production of electrical spikes on a polygraph seen in Electroencephalogram tests (EEG) (de Nijs et al., 2012). Juvenile myoclonic epilepsy accounts for the most prevalent form of an idiopathic disease, where many doctors are completely oblivious to the actual cause of the seizures. Nonetheless, postmortem analysis reveals novel discoveries in the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills or Blood Ties? How Should America Proceed in its Immigration Policies?</title>
      <link>/blog/skills-or-blood-ties-how-should-america-proceed-in-its-immigration-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/skills-or-blood-ties-how-should-america-proceed-in-its-immigration-policies/</guid>
      <description>Policy making is a tricky business. Politicians who confront each other on international issues know the repercussions of each statement they make. Recently, an ongoing fiery debate regarding America’s famous immigration policy has ignited not only national but also international passions and fears. While some citizens may argue that a significant portion of immigrant visas be allocated to those who have some set of skills, others disagree and advocate blood ties as the defining factor in immigration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case of Death Penalties - Should Whether You Live Depend on Where You Live?</title>
      <link>/blog/should-whether-you-live-depend-on-where-you-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/should-whether-you-live-depend-on-where-you-live/</guid>
      <description>Although most, if not all, American citizens deem equality, liberty and respect of life as fundamental aspects of any society, they seem not to be on the same page regarding the prospect of death penalty. Under the New Federalism which governs American politics, the federal system gives considerable power to the individual states over what policies to make and abide by. Although it may seem rudimentary to hark back on the era where a national standard is set for every policy, one may consider it necessary for the aspect of death penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Python in Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>/blog/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python/</guid>
      <description>In bioinformatics, k-mers refer to all the possible subsequences (of length k) from a read obtained through DNA sequencing. For example, if the DNA sequencing read is “ATCATCATG”, then a the 3-mers in that read include “ATC” (which occurs twice), “TCA” (which occurs twice), “CAT” (occurs twice), and “ATG” (occurs once). You can read more about k-mers on Wikipedia.
Here is a function that takes a string of nucleotides as input and returns a dictionary with all 3-mers present in that string, and the number of times that each 3-mer occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION The two datasets chosen are MathAchieve and MathAchSchool. Both relate Achievement Scores in Mathematics to different variables which have been the focus of study for many articles in the modern world. MathAchieve contains the School number, status of being a Minority, Sex of the individual, Socioeconomic Status (SES), a numeric vector of mathematics achievement score (MathAch), and a numeric vector of the mean SES for the entire school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>#Data Sets library(nlme) library(tidyverse) MathAchSchool-&amp;gt; MathAchSchool2 head(MathAchSchool2) ## School Size Sector PRACAD DISCLIM HIMINTY MEANSES ## 1224 1224 842 Public 0.35 1.597 0 -0.428 ## 1288 1288 1855 Public 0.27 0.174 0 0.128 ## 1296 1296 1719 Public 0.32 -0.137 1 -0.420 ## 1308 1308 716 Catholic 0.96 -0.622 0 0.534 ## 1317 1317 455 Catholic 0.95 -1.694 1 0.351 ## 1358 1358 1430 Public 0.25 1.535 0 -0.014 The dataset in question is that of a school demographic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>***This is subject to edit and changes
EDUCATION
• 2015 Completed University of Cambridge, GCE Ordinary and Advanced Levels (High School)
• 2017-2020 Enrolled in the University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX – Bachelor of Science in Biology (Pre-Med) Graduation Date: Spring 2020 Concentration in Upper-Dvision Biology; Cumulative GPA = 3.86 (as of current)
• 2019 MCAT score of 509
• 2020-21 Enrolled in a Masters in Public Health (Epidemiology) at the University of Health Sciences Center in Houston</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>