<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Taimur Hassan</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Taimur Hassan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Look What I Found!</title>
      <link>/blog/look-what-i-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/look-what-i-found/</guid>
      <description>MY FIRST EVER GIF PROJECT. CLEARLY, THE MESSAGE IS DIFFICULT TO UNDERSTAND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutations in EFHC1 gene influencing brain development in patients with JME</title>
      <link>/blog/mutations-in-efhc1-gene-influencing-brain-development-in-patients-with-jme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mutations-in-efhc1-gene-influencing-brain-development-in-patients-with-jme/</guid>
      <description>Juvenile Myoclonic Epilepsy presents itself in adolescence, affecting the person’s well-being (Striano &amp;amp; Nobile, 2018). It presents itself in myoclonic jerks causing the production of electrical spikes on a polygraph seen in Electroencephalogram tests (EEG) (de Nijs et al., 2012). Juvenile myoclonic epilepsy accounts for the most prevalent form of an idiopathic disease, where many doctors are completely oblivious to the actual cause of the seizures. Nonetheless, postmortem analysis reveals novel discoveries in the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should whether you live depend on where you live?</title>
      <link>/blog/should-whether-you-live-depend-on-where-you-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/should-whether-you-live-depend-on-where-you-live/</guid>
      <description>Although most, if not all, American citizens deem equality, liberty and respect of life as fundamental aspects of any society, they seem not to be on the same page regarding the prospect of death penalty. Under the New Federalism which governs American politics, the federal system gives considerable power to the individual states over what policies to make and abide by. Although it may seem rudimentary to hark back on the era where a national standard is set for every policy, one may consider it necessary for the aspect of death penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills or Blood Ties? How Should America Proceed in its Immigration Policies?</title>
      <link>/blog/skills-or-blood-ties-how-should-america-proceed-in-its-immigration-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/skills-or-blood-ties-how-should-america-proceed-in-its-immigration-policies/</guid>
      <description>Policy making is a tricky business. Politicians who confront each other on international issues know the repercussions of each statement they make. Recently, an ongoing fiery debate regarding America’s famous immigration policy has ignited not only national but also international passions and fears. While some citizens may argue that a significant portion of immigrant visas be allocated to those who have some set of skills, others disagree and advocate blood ties as the defining factor in immigration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image of my Favorite Musical Instrument</title>
      <link>/blog/image-of-my-favorite-musical-instrument/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/image-of-my-favorite-musical-instrument/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Work</title>
      <link>/blog/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python/</guid>
      <description>In bioinformatics, k-mers refer to all the possible subsequences (of length k) from a read obtained through DNA sequencing. For example, if the DNA sequencing read is “ATCATCATG”, then a the 3-mers in that read include “ATC” (which occurs twice), “TCA” (which occurs twice), “CAT” (occurs twice), and “ATG” (occurs once). You can read more about k-mers on Wikipedia.
Here is a function that takes a string of nucleotides as input and returns a dictionary with all 3-mers present in that string, and the number of times that each 3-mer occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>